Hello everyone and welcome back to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我的名字是马可。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today with Erika we have an upper intermediate lesson.
今天和Erika一起，我们要上一节中高级课程。
That's right, an upper intermediate lesson that's a little bit strange.
没错，这是一节有点奇怪的中高级课程。
It's a little bit strange but it's a real English lesson because that's what we give
这有点奇怪，但这是一堂真正的英语课，因为我们就是这样教的。
you here at EnglishPod.
你现在收听的是EnglishPod。
So in today's lesson we've got a lot of really great language for you.
那么，在今天的课程中，我们为你准备了很多非常棒的语言表达。
We've got language to help you to gossip better.
我们有一些语言技巧，能帮你更好地八卦。
Gossip, why don't you explain it a little bit just in case.
八卦，要不你稍微解释一下，以防万一。
Okay so if I gossip, I maybe share news or information about other people with my friends.
好吧，如果我八卦，我可能会和朋友分享关于其他人的新闻或信息。
Like I might say something like, Marco, did you see what happened in ChinesePod today?
比如我可能会说，Marco，你看到今天ChinesePod发生了什么吗？
You'll never guess what I saw.
你绝对猜不到我看到了什么。
Exactly, that's gossip.
没错，那就是八卦。
And we also have language today to describe things.
今天我们也有用来描述事物的语言。
To describe strange things.
用来描述奇怪的事物。
Strange things.
奇怪的事物。
Alright so let's take a look at our vocabulary preview.
好的，让我们来看看词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
So in our vocabulary preview we'll look at a few important words that will help you to
在词汇预览中，我们会看一些重要的单词，它们会帮助你……
understand the dialogue a little bit better.
更好地理解对话。
Exactly and the first word is weird.
没错，第一个词是 weird。
Weird.
Weird。
Now this is a common word you probably hear all the time and in a lot of different situations.
这是一个很常见的词，你可能经常听到，在很多不同的场合。
So we wanted to explain it today.
所以我们今天想解释一下它。
Yeah, this word just means strange.
是的，这个词的意思就是奇怪。
It's strange.
就是奇怪。
Yeah.
对。
Weird person is a strange person.
怪人就是奇怪的人。
Yeah, exactly.
对，没错。
But the thing about this word is if you are a young person, let's say under the age of
但这个词的问题是，如果你是年轻人，比如说35岁以下，
35, you'll probably use it about a hundred times a day.
你一天可能会用上一百次。
Weird.
怪。
Yeah.
是啊。
It's just such a good sounding word, weird.
这个词听起来就是很顺耳，怪。
It is.
确实。
Okay but the thing is that even though it is probably more commonly used in American
好吧，但问题是，尽管这个词可能更常用于美式英语，
English, it's still widely used for British English as well.
它在英式英语中同样广泛使用。
Yeah, that's true.
是啊，没错。
So but maybe in British English you would say something like...
不过也许在英式英语里你会说像……
Odd.
奇怪。
Yeah.
对。
That's more common.
那更常见。
Okay, let's look at our second word.
好，我们来看第二个词。
Housewarming gift.
乔迁礼物。
Now this is a cultural thing.
这跟文化有关。
It's really common in North America to give a housewarming gift to someone.
在北美，送乔迁礼物给别人很常见。
Yeah, if I move into a new house, maybe some of my friends or family will bring a gift
对，如果我搬新家，朋友或家人可能会带礼物来。
over to make my house a little bit more beautiful.
让我的房子更漂亮一些。
So something like a photo frame or...
比如相框之类的……
Or maybe a plant or sometimes even like maybe a basket of pastries or something.
或者一盆植物，有时甚至是一篮糕点什么的。
Okay.
好吧。
Yeah.
嗯。
I've never gotten one of those because I don't have a home.
我从没收到过，因为我没有家。
Oh.
哦。
Where do you live?
你住哪儿？
On the street?
住街上？
Well, I don't have my own home so I have never gotten one of those.
嗯，我没有自己的家，所以从没收到过。
Okay.
好吧。
Okay, so we're ready now to listen to our dialogue.
好，现在我们准备听对话。
So we've got two housewives who are gossiping about what's going on in the neighborhood
有两个家庭主妇在闲聊邻居的事。
and let's listen to what happens.
我们来听听发生了什么。
Oh, I don't know if you've heard, but someone moved into that old house down the road.
哦，不知道你听说了没，有人搬进了路那头的老房子。
Yeah, I know.
嗯，我知道。
I met the owner of the house yesterday as he was moving in.
昨天他搬家时我遇到了房主。
His name is Armand.
他叫阿曼德。
Really?
真的？
What's he like?
他怎么样？
You have to fill me in.
你得跟我说说。
Actually, he's a bit strange.
其实他有点奇怪。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I've just got a bad feeling about him.
就是对他有种不好的感觉。
Really?
真的？
Why?
为什么？
Yesterday I brought over a housewarming gift, but Armand started acting really weird and
昨天我带了一份乔迁礼物过去，但阿曼德开始表现得很奇怪，然后
then he practically kicked me out.
他几乎把我赶了出来。
I tried to sort of peek into his house, but everything was so dark inside that I couldn't
我试着往他屋里瞥了一眼，但里面太暗了，我根本
really get a good look.
看不清楚。
The whole thing really creeped me out.
整件事真的把我吓坏了。
Well, you'll never guess what I saw this morning.
你绝对猜不到我今天早上看到了什么。
A delivery truck pulled into his driveway and it dropped off a long rectangular box.
一辆送货卡车开进了他的车道，卸下了一个长方形的箱子。
It almost looked like a coffin.
看起来几乎像一口棺材。
You see?
你看吧？
Why would he?
他为什么要……？
Hello, ladies.
女士们，你们好。
Armand!
阿曼德！
Oh, you scared the heck out of me.
哦，你吓死我了。
This is my friend Doris.
这是我的朋友多丽丝。
Pleasure to meet you.
很高兴认识你。
If you're not doing anything tonight, I'd like to have you both for dinner.
如果你们今晚没事的话，我想请你们俩吃饭。
I mean, I'd like to have you both over for dinner.
我是说，我想请你们俩来家里吃饭。
Ooh, that guy seems kind of weird.
哦，那家伙看起来有点怪。
You can hear his voice is like a weird guy, right?
你能听出他的声音像个怪人，对吧？
Yeah.
是啊。
All right, let's take a look at our language takeaway and look at some of these great words.
好了，我们来看看今天的语言要点，学习一些重要的词汇。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
So, our language takeaway focuses on several words from the dialogue that we feel are really
我们的语言要点聚焦于对话中的几个单词，我们认为这些单词对你们来说
important for you to know.
非常重要。
Exactly, and we have four of them for you today.
没错，今天我们为大家准备了四个单词。
Why don't we look at the first one?
我们先来看第一个吧？
Okay, so the first word is a bad feeling.
好的，第一个词是“不好的预感”。
Bad feeling.
不好的预感。
A bad feeling.
So, we've got a few examples that will help you to understand how this phrase works.
我们有几个例子可以帮助你理解这个短语的用法。
Example one.
例子一。
I don't like Kelly's new boyfriend.
我不喜欢凯莉的新男友。
I've got a bad feeling about him.
我对他有种不好的预感。
Example two.
例子二。
It's so dark.
天太黑了。
We shouldn't be out here.
我们不应该待在这里。
I've got a bad feeling about this.
我对此有种不好的预感。
Example three.
例子三。
I've got a bad feeling about this trip.
我对这次旅行有种不好的预感。
I feel like something's going to happen.
我感觉有什么事要发生。
Maybe we shouldn't go.
也许我们不该去。
Okay, so basically you think something bad is going to happen.
好吧，所以基本上你觉得会有坏事发生。
Yeah, you have a sort of uncomfortable feeling.
对，你有一种不舒服的感觉。
Okay, that makes sense.
好吧，有道理。
You have a bad feeling about something.
你对某事有种不好的预感。
Exactly.
没错。
Okay, let's look at our second word now.
好，现在我们来看第二个词。
Kicked me out.
把我赶出去。
So when someone kicks you out, it's they force you to leave.
所以当有人把你赶出去，就是他们强迫你离开。
You don't want to leave, but they force you to.
你不想离开，但他们强迫你。
Yeah.
对。
Marco, have you ever kicked someone out of your class?
Marco，你有没有把学生赶出过课堂？
Yes, I have.
有过。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah, if you misbehave in my class, you're kicked out.
是的，如果在我课堂上行为不端，就会被赶出去。
So you're pretty strict, huh?
所以你挺严格的，是吧？
Sometimes I am.
有时候是。
Okay.
好吧。
So maybe you've kicked your husband out of bed.
也许你把你丈夫赶下过床。
I might have done that once or twice before.
我可能做过一两次。
We'll have to ask him.
我们得问问他。
I'm sure he has.
我肯定他有过。
All right, so that's what it means.
好了，这就是它的意思。
You force someone to leave the house, leave the class, leave the bed.
你强迫某人离开房子、离开课堂、离开床。
So kicked out of class, kicked out of the house, kicked out of bed.
所以被赶出课堂、被赶出房子、被赶下床。
Exactly.
没错。
Great.
很好。
Let's look at our third word now.
现在我们来看第三个词。
Creeped me out.
把我吓坏了。
Now this is a really common phrase.
这是一个非常常用的短语。
I like this phrase a lot, and we've got some examples for you to listen to to help you
我很喜欢这个短语，我们准备了一些例子让你听，帮助你
understand this word a little bit better.
更好地理解这个词。
Example one.
例子一。
Shh.
嘘。
Did you hear that?
你听到了吗？
Oh, I think I saw something.
哦，我好像看到了什么东西。
Stop it.
别这样。
You're really creeping me out.
你真的把我吓坏了。
Example two.
例子二。
This place really creeps me out.
这地方真让我毛骨悚然。
Let's get out of here.
我们快离开这里吧。
All right, well, I have a confession to make.
好吧，我得坦白一件事。
I'm kind of creeped out by clowns.
我有点害怕小丑。
You are?
是吗？
Yes.
是的。
I don't know.
我不知道。
They're just creepy.
他们就是很吓人。
They scare me.
他们让我害怕。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
嗯。
What is it about clowns that scare you so much?
小丑到底哪里让你这么害怕？
I don't know.
我不知道。
They're just white faces and weird paint.
就是那些白色的脸和奇怪的妆容。
I don't know.
我不知道。
It's just creepy.
就是很吓人。
And the way they laugh.
还有他们笑的样子。
I don't know.
我不知道。
Maybe you had a bad experience with clowns as a child.
也许你小时候有过关于小丑的糟糕经历。
Probably.
可能吧。
I watched a scary movie about clowns or something.
我看过一部关于小丑的恐怖电影之类的。
Yeah.
嗯。
All right.
好吧。
So, creeped me out basically means made me feel uncomfortable.
所以，creeped me out 基本上就是让我感到不舒服的意思。
Yes.
是的。
It scares you.
它让你害怕。
Yeah.
嗯。
Well, speaking of being scared, we have our final word for language takeaway, and it is
说到害怕，我们语言学习的最后一个词是
scared the heck out of me.
把我吓了个半死。
You scared the heck out of me.
你把我吓了个半死。
Scared the heck out of me.
把我吓了个半死。
You got really scared.
你被吓得不轻。
Yeah, I think this is a quite common way of saying, you really, really scared me.
是的，我觉得这是一种很常见的说法，意思是你真的、真的吓到我了。
Yeah.
嗯。
Okay.
好的。
We're ready to listen to our dialogue again.
我们准备好再听一遍对话了。
Now, try and see if you can catch all these phrases that we just talked about.
现在，试着看看你能不能抓住我们刚才讨论的所有短语。
Oh, I don't know if you've heard, but someone moved into that old house down the road.
哦，不知道你听说了没，有人搬进了路那头的老房子。
Yeah, I know.
嗯，我知道。
I met the owner of the house yesterday as he was moving in.
我昨天在房主搬进来的时候遇到了他。
His name is Armand.
他叫阿曼德。
Really?
真的吗？
What's he like?
他怎么样？
You have to fill me in.
你得跟我讲讲。
Actually, he's a bit strange.
其实，他有点奇怪。
I don't know.
我不知道。
I've just got a bad feeling about him.
我就是对他有种不好的感觉。
Really?
真的吗？
Why?
为什么？
Well, yesterday I brought over a housewarming gift, but Armand started acting really weird,
嗯，昨天我带了一份乔迁礼物过去，但阿曼德开始表现得很奇怪，
and then he practically kicked me out.
然后他几乎把我赶了出来。
I tried to sort of peek into his house, but everything was so dark inside that I couldn't
我试着往他屋里瞥了一眼，但里面太暗了，我根本
really get a good look.
看不清楚。
The whole thing really creeped me out.
整件事让我毛骨悚然。
Well, you'll never guess what I saw this morning.
那你绝对猜不到我今天早上看到了什么。
A delivery truck pulled into his driveway and it dropped off a long rectangular box.
一辆送货卡车开进了他的车道，卸下了一个长方形的箱子。
It almost looked like a coffin.
看起来几乎像一口棺材。
You see, why would he—
你看，他为什么要——
Hello, ladies.
女士们，你们好。
Ah, Armand.
啊，阿曼德。
You scared the heck out of me.
你吓死我了。
This is my friend, Doris.
这是我的朋友，多丽丝。
A pleasure to meet you.
很高兴认识你。
If you are not doing anything tonight, I would like to have you both for dinner.
如果你们今晚没事的话，我想请你们俩吃晚饭。
I mean, I would like to have you both over for dinner.
我是说，我想请你们俩来家里吃晚饭。
You know, one of the things I really like about this dialogue is there's a lot of great
你知道，我真的很喜欢这段对话的一点是，里面有很多很棒的
phrases that will help you to gossip.
短语能帮你八卦。
That's a good observation.
观察得好。
So I think it's time for Fluency Builder.
所以我觉得是时候进入流利度构建环节了。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
In Fluency Builder, we take a simple phrase or a simple word you already know and show
在流利度构建中，我们会拿一个你已经知道的简单短语或单词，然后展示
you how to express the same idea a little bit more naturally.
你如何更自然地表达同样的意思。
Okay, great.
好的，太好了。
So let's take a look at our first item for Fluency Builder.
那我们来看看流利度构建的第一个项目。
So when you gossip with somebody, you often tell them news or information that they don't
所以当你和别人闲聊时，你常常会告诉他们一些他们还不知道的消息或信息。
know already.
已经知道的事情。
And you might start by saying, did you know that?
你可能会以“你知道吗？”开头。
Or you can say, did you hear?
或者你可以说：“你听说了吗？”
Yeah, both of those phrases are perfectly fine, but if you want to sound a little bit
是的，这两种说法都没问题，但如果你想在闲聊时听起来更地道一些，
more native-like when you're gossiping, you might try out this phrase from the dialogue.
你可以试试对话中的这个短语。
I don't know if you've heard.
我不知道你有没有听说过。
Yeah, that's a really good phrase.
是的，这个短语真不错。
You're saying exactly the same thing, but in a really natural way.
你说的意思完全一样，但表达方式非常自然。
It's a great one for gossiping.
这是闲聊时的一个好用法。
So Marco, I don't know if you've heard, but ChinesePod is up to some pretty crazy things.
所以 Marco，我不知道你有没有听说，但 ChinesePod 正在搞一些很疯狂的事情。
See, that's exactly how you would use that phrase.
看，这就是这个短语的用法。
So now let's take a look at our second item.
现在我们来看第二个要点。
Now when you're gossiping, you want information.
当你闲聊时，你想要获取信息。
That's right.
没错。
So you might say, oh, tell me about it.
所以你可能会说：“哦，跟我说说。”
Or something like, give me the details.
或者像“给我详细说说”之类的。
Yeah, and again, both of these examples are perfectly fine, but when you're gossiping,
是的，同样，这两个例子都没问题，但当你闲聊时，
you might want to try something like this.
你可能会想试试这样的说法。
You have to fill me in.
你得给我讲讲。
Fill me in, yeah, that's what I would say.
给我讲讲，是的，我会这么说。
Fill me in, you know, give me the details.
给我讲讲，你知道，就是告诉我细节。
Fill me in.
给我讲讲。
Fill me in on today's gossip.
给我讲讲今天的八卦。
Okay, so let's take a look at our third item.
好的，我们来看第三个要点。
Now if you have some juicy gossipy news and you want to start up a conversation, you might
如果你有一些劲爆的八卦消息，想开启一段对话，你可能会
use this phrase here.
用这个短语。
Well, you'll never guess what I saw this morning.
嗯，你绝对猜不到我今天早上看到了什么。
That's a really good phrase.
这个短语真不错。
You can change it a little bit.
你可以稍微改一下。
You can say, you'll never guess who I saw.
你可以说：“你绝对猜不到我见到了谁。”
Or you'll never guess what I heard.
或者“你绝对猜不到我听到了什么。”
Exactly.
没错。
Very excellent gossip phrases.
非常棒的八卦短语。
We're teaching you how to gossip because that's real English.
我们教你如何八卦，因为这才是真实的英语。
People really do it, so you've got to know the language for it.
人们确实会这么做，所以你必须学会相关的语言。
All right, so enough of our gossip.
好了，我们的八卦就到这里。
I think it's time for us to listen to the dialogue one last time.
我想是时候再听一遍对话了。
Oh, I don't know if you've heard, but someone moved into that old house down the road.
哦，不知道你听说了没，有人搬进了路那头的老房子。
Yeah, I know.
嗯，我知道。
I met the owner of the house yesterday as he was moving in.
昨天他搬进来的时候我遇到了房主。
His name is Armand.
他叫阿曼德。
Really?
真的吗？
What's he like?
他怎么样？
You have to fill me in.
你得跟我讲讲。
Actually, he's a bit strange.
其实，他有点奇怪。
I don't know.
我也说不上来。
I've just got a bad feeling about him.
就是对他有种不好的感觉。
Really?
真的吗？
Why?
为什么？
Well, yesterday I brought over a housewarming gift, but Armand started acting really weird,
嗯，昨天我带了乔迁礼物过去，但阿曼德开始表现得很奇怪，
and then he practically kicked me out.
然后他几乎把我赶了出来。
I tried to sort of peek into his house, but everything was so dark inside that I couldn't
我试着往他屋里瞥了一眼，但里面太暗了，我根本
really get a good look.
看不清楚。
The whole thing really creeped me out.
整件事让我毛骨悚然。
Well, you'll never guess what I saw this morning.
那你绝对猜不到我今天早上看到了什么。
A delivery truck pulled into his driveway, and it dropped off a long rectangular box.
一辆送货卡车开进了他的车道，卸下了一个长长的长方形箱子。
It almost looked like a coffin.
看起来几乎像一口棺材。
You see?
你看吧？
Why would he?
他为什么要……
Hello, ladies.
女士们，你们好。
Armand!
阿曼德！
You scared the heck out of me.
你吓死我了。
This is my friend Doris.
这是我的朋友多丽丝。
A pleasure to meet you.
很高兴认识你。
If you're not doing anything tonight, I'd like to have you both for dinner.
如果你们今晚没事，我想请你们俩吃饭。
I mean, I'd like to have you both over for dinner.
我是说，我想请你们俩来家里吃饭。
Okay, Markle, I have a true story for you.
好的，马克尔，我有个真实故事要讲给你听。
Is it kind of like a creepy story?
是那种恐怖故事吗？
It is a creepy story indeed.
确实是个恐怖故事。
Is it a true story?
是真实故事吗？
No, it's really true.
不，是真的真实故事。
So, when I was young, I used to live in the country.
我小时候住在乡下。
And you know, in the country, all of the neighbors know each other.
你知道，在乡下，邻居们都互相认识。
It's a small community, so everyone knows what's happening all the time.
那是个小社区，所以大家总是知道发生了什么。
And there was some gossip going on in our community about a guy who lived at the end
我们社区里有些关于住在路尽头的一个家伙的闲话，
of the road.
在路的尽头。
And he was the owner of a car wrecking yard.
他是一家汽车报废场的老板。
So a place where you take old broken down cars and take the parts apart to sell.
就是那种你把破旧汽车送去，拆下零件卖的地方。
Right.
对。
And anyway, a scrap yard.
总之，是个废车场。
Yeah, a scrap yard.
对，废车场。
All right.
好吧。
Okay, so, you know, he had a wife and a couple of kids.
好，他有个妻子和几个孩子。
And suddenly his wife disappeared.
突然他妻子失踪了。
Wow.
哇。
Yeah.
是啊。
And no one knew what happened or anything.
没人知道发生了什么。
And so several years pass and suddenly the police start coming in and start investigating
几年过去了，警察突然开始调查这个人，在他家周围到处挖掘。
this guy and start digging up all of the land around his property.
他们在他家周围的所有土地上挖掘。
And I guess, I don't know what they're doing, but I think they were looking for the wife's
我不知道他们在干什么，但我觉得他们在找妻子的尸体。
body.
尸体。
Wow.
哇。
And did they find it?
他们找到了吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
I moved away.
我搬走了。
Oh, such a great story, but we don't know how it ends.
哦，这么精彩的故事，我们却不知道结局。
Yeah.
是啊。
Well, we can leave it up to the imagination of our listeners.
那就留给听众们去想象吧。
Exactly.
没错。
Maybe they were looking for an old car.
也许他们是在找一辆旧车。
An old car buried in the ground.
一辆埋在地下的旧车。
I don't think so.
我不这么认为。
All right.
好吧。
That's a true story.
这是个真实的故事。
Real English, real stories.
真实的英语，真实的故事。
You heard it first here on EnglishPod.
你第一次听到是在EnglishPod。
All right.
好吧。
So, we want to hear your comments and suggestions about this topic.
我们想听听你们对这个话题的评论和建议。
I bet a lot of our listeners also have creepy stories, maybe ghost stories, maybe, I don't
我敢肯定很多听众也有恐怖故事，也许是鬼故事，或者各种奇怪的故事。
know, different types of weird stories.
各种奇怪的故事。
So, you guys should definitely log on to EnglishPod and share them with us.
所以你们一定要登录EnglishPod，和我们分享。
That's right.
没错。
Go to EnglishPod.com and in the comment section of the website, tell us your creepy stories.
去EnglishPod.com，在网站的评论区告诉我们你的恐怖故事。
And we're going to pick out the best story as the story of the week.
我们会选出最好的故事作为本周故事。
We'll announce it in our This Just In podcast.
我们会在《This Just In》播客中公布。
Yes.
是的。
So, we want to hear all your juicy stories and gossip maybe as well.
所以，我们想听听你所有的劲爆故事，也许还有八卦。
Yes.
是的。
All right.
好的。
Well, it's time for us to go.
嗯，我们该走了。
So, be sure to listen to us next time.
所以，请务必下次收听我们的节目。
But until then, it's...
但在那之前，这是……
Bye-bye.
再见。
Bye.